Are you all enjoying the holiday?
여러분 연휴 잘 보내고 계신가요?
Hello, where am I? I'm on my way to the radio station.
안녕하세요 저는 어디지? 배텐을 가고 있어요
So, I decided to do a live broadcast after a long time.
그래서 오랜만에 라방을 켰습니다
I was wondering if our Lovelinus are resting well during the holiday? Are you ready for the radio show?
우리 러블리너스들 연휴 잘 쉬고 있나? 배텐들을 준비가 됐나? 싶어가지고
I turned on the live because it's been such a long time and I feel sorry about it.
이렇게 켰는데 너무 오랜만에 라방 켜서 미안하기도 하고
I've kept it on.
계속 켰어요
You're all doing well, right?
다들 잘 지내고 있죠?
Let's do this.
음 이렇게 해야겠다
Right now, Brother Seongjae is in Qatar, so
네 배성재에텐 지금 성재오빠가 카타르에 계셔서
I'm acting as the special DJ for the radio this week.
제가 이번주는 라디오 스페셜 DJ를 하고 있거든요
We have a live broadcast at 10 PM tonight.
다들 이따 밤 10시에 생방송 하거든요
Where can you watch it?
어디로 가야 볼 수 있지?
EraoTV?
에라오TV?
Anyway, something on the internet.
뭐 하여튼 뭐 인터넷으로
You can find out how to watch it by searching online, right?
인터넷 검색하면 어떻게 보는지 알 수 있지 않겠습니까?
Ah, you can watch it there too.
아 거기서도 볼 수 있다
If you search "Bae Seongjae" on KakaoTV, you'll probably find it.
카카오티비에 배성재치고 들어오면 아마 볼 수 있을걸요?
Anyway, since it's a radio you can see,
뭐 하여튼 보이는 라디오니까
if you have time, please watch the radio show as well.
시간 괜찮으신 분들은 배텐도 봐주시고
It's been a while since I've done a live,
네 오랜만에 라방 켜니까
seeing our Insta-friends after such a long time
오랜만에 보는 저희 인친들
is really nice.
아주 반가워요
Have you all gone to your hometowns?
다들 고향은 내려갔어요?
Lip? Uh, I'm not sure what that is.
립? 어 립 뭔지 모르겠다
I'm not sure what lip is, sorry.
립 뭔지 모르겠어요 죄송합니다
I'm not sure about the lip.
립 뭔지 모르겠어
Dinner is a banana.
저녁은 바나나
Because last night,
왜냐면 어제 저녁에
I ate too much. I ate too much for dinner.
너무 많이 먹었어요. 저녁에 너무 많이 먹어서
So today, I'm going to make do with a banana.
오늘은 바나나로 떼울 겁니다.
"Unnie, you're going to have a fan meeting this year too, right?"
"누나 올해도 팬미팅 할거죠?"
I really want to do it too,
저도 너무 하고싶어서
so I'll try to make it happen.
할 수 있게 끔 잘 한번 만들어 볼게요
I can't promise,
장담은 못하지만
Hold on, I'll peel a banana.
잠시만요 바나나를 깔게요
But I thought it had warmed up a bit, but it's still a bit cold today.
근데 날씨가 좀 풀린 줄 알았는데 오늘도 좀 춥더라구요
Peeling a banana.
바나나 까기
Eating a banana like this
이렇게 바나나를 먹고
and drinking milk,
우유를 먹으면
makes it banana milk.
바나나 우유
"Finishing the day happily after seeing the live broadcast after work."
"일 끝나고 폰 보니까 라방한다 너무 행복한 하루 마무리"
Thank you, Haruka.
고마워요 하루카
It's really been a while since I drank milk,
우유를 진짜 오랜만에 마시는데
and it tastes good after a long time, doesn't it?
오랜만에 먹으니까
Milk is tasty?
맛있는데요 우유가?
When I was young, I used to drink plain milk reluctantly.
어릴 땐 흰 우유를 억지로 먹었거든요
As I grew up,
역시 크면서
it seems my taste has changed.
입맛이 변하는 것 같습니다
There was plain milk for school meals when I was young, right?
어릴 때 흰 우유 급식 있었죠
When I was young, I drank it reluctantly and mixed it with all sorts of things,
어릴 땐 좀 억지로 먹고 막 제티를 막 타먹고 막 그랬는데
but nowadays, I drink plain milk just fine.
요즘에는 뭐 흰 우유도 잘 먹습니다
Everyone,
다들
have you gone to your hometown?
본가에 가셨나요?
I really enjoy watching ELLE Dong videos.
엘르동(ELLE Dong) 영상 너무너무 잘 보고 있어요
Thank you.
감사합니다
I also enjoy watching my ELLE Dong videos.
저도 저의 엘르동 영상을 잘 보고 있어요
"I can't go to my hometown, so I'll sleep watching the radio show."
"본가 못가서 배텐보고 자려고요"
Good idea.
좋은 생각
I saw the WABAR video earlier, thank you.
저 아까 와바(WABAR) 영상 봤어요 감사합니다
I happened to connect with Brother Wadi like this,
제가 또 와디 오빠랑 연이 이렇게 생겨서
so we filmed together.
같이 촬영을 했는데
It was really fun.
아주 재밌었습니다
I'm not going to my hometown.
저는 본가에 안 가요
I'm not going to my hometown,
저는 본가에 안 가고
because I have things to do in Seoul.
서울에서 할 일들이 있어서
So, I think I'll be in Seoul.
서울에 있을 것 같습니다
But really, eating just one banana and milk together gives a lot of satiety.
근데 진짜 바나나 하나랑 우유랑 같이 먹으면 약간
It feels very filling.
되게 포만감이 많은 것 같아요
My stomach is too full.
배가 너무 부르고
My stomach is really full.
배가 너무 부릅니다
The one I just ate is the second one.
방금 먹은 게 두 개째예요
I ate one at home earlier,
아까 집에서 하나 먹었고
and I thought I might get hungry again,
뭔가 또 배고플 것 같아서
so I ate another one in the car.
차에서 또 하나 먹고
Ah, so I was at Tokoya, I left my hat again,
아 그니까 도코야 내가 있잖아 모자를 또 두고 가가지고
please take good care of that hat for me.
그 모자 좀 잘 맡겨줘 맡아줘
I always leave something behind.
맨날 하나씩 두고 오네요
Anyway, that's how it is.
하튼 그렇튼
Please watch, everyone. Today is the last day.
봐주세요 여러분 오늘이 마지막이에요
But the things we've pre-recorded will go out on the radio on Saturday and Sunday,
하러 가는 거는 근데 이제 녹방 해둔 것들이
and they're already up on YouTube,
토요일이랑 일요일에 라디오로 나갈 거고
so everything that's been prepared will be available.
유튜브에는 이미 녹방을 해놔서
Today is already the last day, but the radio has been
다 뜹니다 해놓은 게
so much fun.
오늘이 벌써 마지막이에요 근데 저 라디오가
What are you all doing during the holiday?
너무 재밌어요
What are your plans for the holiday?
저 연휴에 뭐하고 쉴까요 여러분
Have you all gone to your hometown?
여러분 연휴 계획이 뭐예요?
Maybe everyone has gone to their hometown.
다 본가에 가셨으려나
Drinking milk with red vinegar, I know what that is.
우유랑 홍초랑 같이 먹는 거 저 뭔지 알아요
It becomes somewhat like yogurt, right?
그러면 약간 요플레처럼 되잖아요 그쵸
What's on sale at Costco these days for 120,000 won?
요새 코스트코에서 할인해서 뭐가 12만원에 팔아요?
But I've arrived at the radio, everyone.
근데 제가 라디오에 도착했어요 여러분
Why can't you go to your hometown?
본가 왜 못가?
During the holiday, it's whiskey.
연휴 땐 위스키죠
Right, whiskey is good, but after finishing work during the holiday,
그쵸 위스키도 좋은데 연휴 때 뭔가 일 끝나고
I feel like drinking wine.
와인이 먹고 싶을 것 같아서
Before coming to the radio show,
아까 배텐 오기 전에
I bought three bottles of wine from a local wine shop.
동네에 있는 와인집에서 와인을 3병이나 샀어요
Two bottles of white wine,
화이트 와인 2개랑
and one bottle of red wine.
레드 와인 하나를 샀는데
One of the white wines is a recent favorite of mine,
화이트 와인은 원래 요 근래 좋아하는 화이트 와인 하나랑
and the other is said to be very similar to that wine but a few ten-thousands of won cheaper.
또 하나는 그 와인이랑 되게 비슷한
So, I was curious about that and bought a bottle of it too.
또 다른 조금 더 가격이 몇만원 저렴한 와인이 있다는 거예요
And I really like Caymus wine,
그래서 그거가 또 궁금해가지고 그것도 한 병 사고
but if you buy it in Korea, it's currently selling for about 140,000 won.
그래서 제가 케이머스 와인을 되게 좋아하는데
But a bottle for 140,000 won isn't exactly cheap, right?
그 와인이 이제 한국에서 사면은 한 14만원 정도에 지금 팔고 있단 말이에요
There are more expensive wines, of course,
근데 한 병이 14만원이면 사실 싼 와인은 아니잖아요
but I got some recommendations for wines similar to Caymus,
그것보다 더 비싼 와인도 많이 있겠지만
and thought about trying a different kind of wine, maybe an American wine since
그래서 케이머스 와인이랑 좀 비슷한 와인들을 추천을 좀 받다가
Caymus is a bit different and an American wine.
케이머스랑은  좀 다른 느낌의 와인도 한번 먹어보면 어떨까 미국 와인 중에
Because Caymus is an American wine.
왜냐면 케이머스는 미국 와인이니까
So, other American wines...
그래서 미국 와인 또다...
Ah! No, no, no.
아! 아니다 아니다 아니다
French wine... No?
프랑스 와인... 아닌데?
Where was it?
어디였지?
Where was it? Gayoung?
어디였지? 가영아?
Ah, where was it? Some...
아 어디였지? 무슨...
That wine is really famous in France,
그 와인이 프랑스가 되게 유명한데
the only one to win 1st place in a blind test.
유일하게 블라인드 테스트를 해서
Which country was it from?
1등한 와인이라고 했는데
What country was it?
어디 나라 거였더라?
Anyway, that's what they say, so
하여튼 뭐 그렇대요 그래서
that...
그...
Not Caymus,
케이머스 말고
I also bought another red wine I'm trying for the first time.
다른 처음 먹어보는 레드 와인도 하나 샀습니다
But Caymus is a bit sweet,
근데 케이머스도 좀 달긴 달거든요
it doesn't show up as having a lot of sugar content when you look it up, but
그게 찾아보면 좀 당도가 그렇게 많다고는 안 나오는데
it tastes sweet to me.
제가 먹기엔 달아요
But it's somewhat sweet and
근데 그 정도로 좀 달고
as rich as Caymus, they said there's another wine like that,
근데 케이머스만큼 되게 진한
so I bought a bottle to try it.
또 다른 와인이라고 해서
That's why I bought three bottles,
그거를 한번 먹어보고자
and it came out to just over 100,000 won.
한 병 샀습니다
Was it 140,000 won?
그래서 그렇게 해서 세 병을 샀는데
One bottle of Caymus is 140,000 won,
10만 원 초반대가 나왔거든요
but today, in thrifty shopping, I got three bottles for 140,000 won.
14만 원인가?
Gotcha!
그 케이머스 한 병이 14만 원인데
Ah, continuously putting on a filter on my hand...
아 필터 입혀서 손에 계속...
This red appearance looks a bit funny.
이거 빨간색 생긴 거 좀 웃기네
I put on a filter today because
오늘은 왜 필터를 입혔냐면
my skin is a bit troubled right now,
제가 지금 피부가 좀 뒤집어져가지고
I first turned it on with the normal quality...
제가 처음에 그냥 일반 화질로 켰는...
I tried like this,
이렇게 해봤는데
but things like this on my forehead, like my skin troubles, are too visible,
너무 그 이마에 이런 거가 너무 잘 보이는 거여서
so today I thought I should push my skin a bit,
오늘은 피부를 좀 밀어야겠다 싶어가지고
That's it. It's been a while since I put on a filter...
다 했습니다. 필터를 오랜만에...
Anyway, I've arrived, so I have to go, everyone.
하여튼 저 도착을 해서 가야 됩니다 여러분
If you want to see me again, please move to the radio show.
이제 제가 또 보고 싶으시면 배텐으로 넘어오시죠
It starts at 10 PM.
10시 시작입니다
Everyone,
여러분
Goodbye, see you again.
빠이 짜이찌엔
Bye.
안녕